<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joy Lin</title>
    <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joy Lin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:55:24 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 22:25:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is one of the most popular open-source static site generators. With its amazing speed and flexibility, Hugo makes building websites fun again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osprey</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/osprey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 21:57:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/osprey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toma Nistor</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/toma-nistor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 20:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/toma-nistor/</guid>
      <description>Author of the original Osprey theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osprey Delight</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/osprey-delight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 21:57:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/osprey-delight/</guid>
      <description>{{! github-description !}}
Check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kdevo</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/kdevo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 22:25:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/gallery/kdevo/</guid>
      <description>Author of Osprey Delight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9: WiFi and Bluetooth (IoT)</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:55:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-9/</guid>
      <description>BLE I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try the BLE subset of the assignment since my team had been thinking about ways to control a drone and BLE was one of the options we were considering.
I followed the instructions on the class website and uploaded the BLE_write program from examples
For the LED specifically, there was this code also on the class website. /* Based on Neil Kolban example for IDF: https://github.com/nkolban/esp32-snippets/blob/master/cpp_utils/tests/BLE%20Tests/SampleWrite.cpp Ported to Arduino ESP32 by Evandro Copercini */ #include &amp;lt;BLEDevice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12: Casting and Molding</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 13:55:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week11/</guid>
      <description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find many small interesting objects around the house so I settled for tossing my d20 into the silicone.
It didn&amp;rsquo;t require too much liquid since it was so small and I was on the cautious side. I also found the narrowest cup in the house to do this with.
A little afraid to cut it out for now, I think it needs to harden a little more.
I want to make ice dodecahderons with the mold, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;d survive a session of DND but it might be fun if the numbers show up on the die.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: Radio Communication</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-8/</guid>
      <description>The whole process of getting the ESP32 Cam working started out with a hiccup. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find board that connected the ESP32CAM to my computer for the longest time because it turned out that I had a different board form everyone else. It didn&amp;rsquo;t make much of a difference because nothing worked after I hooked it up. I tried to upload the Blink code to the board as a test but I got an LED_BUILTIN error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7: Electronic Output Devices</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-7/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Electronic Input Devices</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: 3D Design and Printing</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-5/</guid>
      <description>Photogrammetry I thought it might be good to have a 3D model of the Tile Sticker so that I could have a complete assembly later down the line. I used the Qlone app, probably more hopeful than I should been about the result, and struggled to scan the Tile Sticker for about 15 minutes. The final result:
It came out really deformed on the top and sides, unusable.
3D Print Bike Tile Holder I didn&amp;rsquo;t what I had to secure the two halves with so I dug through the shed toolbox for screws or fasteners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Microcontroller Programming</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-4/</guid>
      <description>Piezobuzzer Circuit I wanted to play some music with a piezo buzzer since I was given the basics in ES50, so I decided to map over knowledge from the class and use the materials from PS70 to make something more extensive.
I used the HUZZAH Feather board instead of the Metro Express or Arduino MKRZero and that required downloading the associated libaries and packets.
TinkerCad Mockup w/Single pin I built a quick circuit in TinkerCad to make sure the LED and Piezobuzzer would work as expected, the only modfication I would have to make to this would be to seperate the pin inputs for the LED and Piezo buzzer since they&amp;rsquo;re controlled differently in the Buzzer code libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Hand Tools and Fabrication</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-3/</guid>
      <description>Fishing reel   Create a kinetic sculpture. Include circuitry to move your sculpture. Control the sculpture with a circuit on a breadboard that uses components in the kit (e.g., resistors, potentiometer). Use a multimeter to measure the voltages in your circuit. Use Ohm&amp;rsquo;s law to calculate current through the circuit. Use the Microcontroller Analog in (ADC) to measure the voltage of a potentiometer, or other voltage-divider-based sensor. (Optional) Use tools like TinkerCAD to simulate your circuit and/or tools like Fusion 360 to design and simulate your mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: 2D Design &amp; Cutting</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-2/</guid>
      <description>Part 1: Circuits I constructed a simple circuit in TinkerCad to see what it&amp;rsquo;s like before building it in real life with the parts in the kit.
Part 2: Press-Fit Kit Since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t constrained by having to make a core mechanism with 2D design this time around, I decided to make a sliced model of a boat with a center mast and two back masts.
Trimaran I did not concern myself with tolerancing and did all the parameters in inches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Intro and Documentation</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/week-1/</guid>
      <description>Documentation and website setup.
Process I was lured into using a static site generator instead of the usual HTML and CSS because it woulld require less coding.
We were given a choice between Hugo or Jekyll and Andrew and I chose the same theme in Hugo, Osprey Delight, to share the burden of learning to manipulate and Sean helped us set it up.
We didn&amp;rsquo;t read the READme and that&amp;rsquo;s where the problems started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/markdown-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/markdown-syntax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placeholder Text</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/placeholder-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/blog/placeholder-text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de pectora summo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look! It&#39;s my PS70 Documentation.</title>
      <link>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 17:39:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://remilarius.github.io/PS70/about/</guid>
      <description>My name&amp;rsquo;s Joy Lin and I&amp;rsquo;m a sophomore in Adams concentrating in Mechanical Engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
